RAMISA ANJUM CHOWDHURY

WEB-DEVELOPER



Full-stack web developer who strives for success and perfection in every given task. Avid and rapid learner with a passion for problem solving and creativity, previously trained as an NHS doctor. Gained certificates in front-end web development and full-stack web development from edX bootcamps and The London App Brewery on Udemy. Highly motivated and reliable with experience working independently and as part of a team and an excellent attitude to work.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Javascript ES6, Bootstrap, AJAX, SASS

Backend: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node, Handlebars, Firebase, AWS, Webpack, Gulp

PROJECTS

PENDING.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Doctor, NHS Aug 2019 – Present

Volunteer Contact Specialist, Flucamp hVIVO

Sept 2017 - Oct 2018

Part-time office-based job, working in a small team to assess and recruit eligible volunteers for Flucamp clinical trials. Role also involves liaising with GP surgeries to obtain medical records as well as various other admin duties.

Customer Assistant, *Tesco Express*

Jul 2016 - Aug 2018

Part-time job working in a busy Express store carrying out various in-store roles including, till-work, age-restricted sales and working stock.

Call Centre Agent, 118 Information Group

Jul 2015 – Aug 2015

Contacting clients, to update business details for listings in directory enquiries. Role required patience and resilience as clients often mistook us for sales representatives. My role improved my communication skills through listening and speaking to many clients and dealing with people not willing to co-operate.

Retail Assistant, *Primark* Aug 2014 – Sept 2014

Part-time job working in a busy Express store carrying out various in-store roles including, till-work, age-restricted sales and working stock.

Filing and Admin Clerk, ABC Teachers

Jun 2014

Temporary job assisting staff within a busy office. My job included general administration work including franking, filing and organising files. My attention to detail is always such that I carry out every job thoroughly.

Retail Assistant, Farmfoods Tamworth

Nov 2012 - Aug 2013

Part-time job working in a small store with various responsibilities including: helping customers, operating the till, stock replenishment, stock takes, delivery work, cleaning the store and cashing up. The store was often busy and only staffed by two people so my job required the ability to work in a fast paced environment, under pressure and required good teamwork, time management, and people skills.

Checkout Operator, ASDA Tamworth

Nov 2012 - Jan 2013

Part-time job working in a large supermarket during the busiest time of the year. I was responsible for processing customer transactions and carrying out appropriate ID checks for age-restricted products.

Warehouse Operative, The Amethyst Group

Jul 2012 - Aug 2012

Full-time job working in a New Look warehouse processing orders and returns. My job required high attention to detail, checking product codes against items to ensure that the correct items were delivered and returned.

Maths and Science KS2/KS3 Tutor, Private Clients

May 2012 - Sept 2013

Part-time role tutoring students of varying ages. My role required good organisation and planning to ensure relevant topics were covered, the ability to vary teaching styles to different levels of understanding and the ability to deliver complicated information in a clear and simplified way.

Administrative Assistant, Brereton Surgery

Jul 2009 - Jun 2013

Part-time employment gained following work experience; carrying out basic office duties handling confidential information and aiding receptionists with their jobs.

EDUCATION

Front-End Web Development Certificate, edX Bootcamps

The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp Certificate, Udemy

Fellowship of the Royal College of Radiologists Part 1 Exam, Royal College of Radiologists

Teach the Teacher Course, Oxford Medical

Conflict Resolution Training, NHS

Medicine (MBBS), Barts and the London School of Medicine and Dentistry

Mar 2024

Mar 2024

Feb 2022

Teach the Teacher Course, Oxford Medical

Jan 2020

Jan 2020

Part 1 Distinction

Part 2 Merit

Biomedical Engineering and Clinical Materials (BSc Hons), Queen Mary University of London Jun 2016

First Class Honors

GCSEs and A-Levels, Queen Mary's Grammar School

Aug 2012

A-levels: Physics (A*) Chemistry (A*) Biology (A) Mathematics (A)

GCSEs: 10 GCSEs (A*-A) including Mathematics (A*) IT (Distinction) Physics (A*)

OCR Free Standing Mathematics Qualification (FSMQ): (A)

AWARDS

The Tallow Chandlers Award for High Academic Achievement
Mathematics Award
Gifted and Talented Award

Mar 2017 Jun 2012 Jun 2008